Peterloo is a history, drama film directed by Mike Leigh.
An epic portrayal of the events surrounding the infamous 1819 Peterloo Massacre, where a peaceful pro-democracy rally at St
Peter’s Field in Manchester turned into one of the bloodiest and most notorious episodes in British history.
The massacre saw British government forces charge into a crowd of over 60,000 that had
gathered to demand political reforms and protest against rising levels of poverty.
Henry Hunt, played by Rory Kinnear.
Nellie, played by Maxine Peake.
Joshua, played by Pearce Quigley.
Joseph, played by David Moorst.
Mary, played by Rachel Finnegan.
Robert, played by Tom Meredith.
Peterloo is a 2018 British historical drama film
written and directed by Mike Leigh.
Based on the Peterloo Massacre of 1819, it stars  Rory
Kinnear, Maxine Peake, and Pearce Quigley.
The film was selected to be screened in the main competition
section of the 75th Venice International Film Festival.
The film received its UK premiere on 17 October 2018, as part of
the BFI London Film Festival, at HOME in Manchester.
The screening marked the first time that the festival
had held a premiere outside London.
Leigh said he was delighted that Peterloo would
be premiered "where it happened".
It was released in the United Kingdom on 2 November 2018, by Entertainment One
and in the United States on 5 April 2019, by Amazon Studios.
The film explores themes of based on true story, massacre,
period drama, british history, historical drama.
The tone is emotional.